Monika Novackova

ADDRESS: School of Global Studies, University of Sussex Personal websites

Falmer, Brighton LinkedIn

BN1 9QJ, United Kingdom

CONTACT DETAILS: 0774 180 4494; monika.novac@gmail.com

CITIZIENSHIP: Czech Republic, EU. Indefinite Leave to Remain in the UK granted

Data scientist, economist and recent PhD graduate is searching for an experience as a data analyst in private sector. Demonstrable skills in advanced statistical analysis and econometric modelling using Python and R. Experienced in communicating concepts to co-workers from various backgrounds.

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Current since 2017

Data analyst in Sustainability, UNIVERSITY OF SUSSEX, Brighton Application of statistical and machine learning methods to analyse effects of droughts on food security using R and Python, hands on data work

Supervisors: Prof. Martin Todd, Dr. Pedram Rowhani

Collected data in a systematic and safe way. Analysed complex data and presented emerging conclusions and concepts. Developed predictive models using R and Excel. Meeting regular deadlines. Working as a part of interdisciplinary team, collaborating with colleagues from diverse professional backgrounds to successfully work towards common goals.

2015-2016

Teaching at THE UNIVERSITY OF SUSSEX, Brighton
Climate Change Economics and Statistical Analysis in STATA

Communicated complex ideas effectively to a range of audiences. Utilized and improved my sensitivity to the needs of others.

2013-2014

WEBCOM A.S., TODAY CONICA MINOLTA IT SOLUTIONS CZECH, Prague Microsoft Dynamics consultant - trainee

Getting experienced in Microsoft Dynamics CRM. Training for the position of CRM consultant. Work shadowing.

2012-2013

Data scientist at CENTRUM WISKUNDE & INFORMATICA (CWI), Amsterdam Statistical analysis and forecasting using R and SOL

Applying methods of quantitative analysis and hands on data work. Presenting and organising large amounts of information in a clear manner. Negotiating skills.

2011

Intern in Data science at PILSNER URQUELL, A.S., Prague Market analysis at the large beer manufacturer

Succeeded in a highly competitive application procedure. Using analytic and statistical skills accompanied with economic background for description and forecasting of beer market dynamics. Improved beer demand models. Presentation of concepts to the company's executive management.

COMPUTER SKILLS

Advanced Knowledge: Python, R, Excel including contingency tables, statistical analysis

simulations and optimization using the Solver Add-In, LaTeX

Intermediate Knowledge: SQL, Git, Web-design (HTML, CSS, JavaScript): Level 1 course run

by Code First: Girls completed in Autumn 2018 (Certificate.pdf)

Basic Knowledge: STATA, ArcGIS, Mathematical Programming (Lingo, Mpl)

EDUCATION

2014-2018 Ph.D. in Economics, University of Sussex, UK

<u>Thesis:</u> "Effects of Sea Level Rise in the United States and climate change perception in the United Kingdom" | Full version

• Hands on data work

• Managing of complex datasets in a range of different formats

• Application of advanced statistical, econometric and ML methods including: Forward stepwise, Variance inflation factors, regularization, OLS, GLMs

Advisors: Prof. Richard Tol, Dr. Alexander Moradi

2011-2013 MSc in Econometrics and Operations Research

Vrije University in Amsterdam

Thesis: "Forecasting of Daily Number of Calls for Firefighters"

• Time series analysis, forecasting, (S)ARIMA models

• Forward stepwise and other econometric, statistical and ML methods

• SQL, working with raw data sets

Advisors: Prof. Siem Jan Koopman, Prof. Michael Massmann

2010-2014 Ing. in Econometrics and Operations Research

Faculty of informatics and statistics, **University of Economics in Prague** <u>Thesis:</u> "Application of Time Series Analysis in Predictive Modelling"

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH: Fluent, PhD completed in English, TOEFL score 101 in 2014

CZECH: Native language

GERMAN: Basic

OTHER ACTIVITIES AND ACHIEVEMENTS

Publication with R. Tol: "Effects of sea level rise on economy of the United States", Journal of Environmental Economics and Policy. DOI:10.1080/21606544.2017.1363667

Presenting at the International Conference of Economics and Development (ICED)
Colombo, Sri Lanka, paper Effects of Sea level rise on land values in the United States

2013 Participation in the Econometric Game 2013 organized by the University of Amsterdam

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

Learning and improving programming skills beyond statistical programming. I have completed a Web-development course run by *Code First: Girls* in Autumn 2018 and I am currently attending the Level 2 course in Python

Sports: Running, Cycling, Snowboarding

References available on request